- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
kids: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
孩子们：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
[flute plays]
[长笛演奏]
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
- Ah, uh...
- 啊，呃...
[whimpering]
[crowd clamoring]
[呜咽]
[人群喧闹]
Hold on! Hold on!
坚持，稍等！坚持，稍等！
Coming right up!
- Now!
马上就来了！
- 现在！
- Give me a second!
- Order up, up, up!
- 等一下！
- 订单增加，订单增加，订单增加！
[clamoring continues]
- Mr. Squidward!
[叫喊声继续]
- 章鱼哥先生！
Why haven't you
taken out the trash?
你为什么没有
把垃圾拿出来了？
- [munching, groans]
- [咀嚼，呻吟]
[crowd clamoring]
- I'm swamped, Mr. Krabs!
[人群喧闹]
- 我被淹没了，蟹老板！
Why are you wearing a towel?
[crowd clamoring]
你为什么戴着毛巾？
[人群喧闹]
- Well, obviously,
I was in me sauna.
- 嗯，显然，
我在桑拿房里。
Being a manager is
hard work, you know?
成为一名经理就是
辛苦你知道吗？
- You have to do better.
- 你必须做得更好。
- Can't you help
me a little bit?
- 你能帮忙吗
我一点点？
- A manager does
not do grunt work.
- 经理这样做
不做繁重的工作。
That's what Squidwards are for.
这就是章鱼哥的用途。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Hmmph!
- 哼！
I deserve to be manager
and sit on my butt all day.
我值得当经理
整天坐在我的屁股上。
But will I ever get promoted?
但我会升职吗？
- Are you tired
of being a loser?
- 你累了吗
成为失败者？
- Yes.
[sputters]
- 是的。
[溅射声]
Wait, who said that?
等等，谁说的？
- Wouldn't you
rather be a weenie?
- 你不会吗
宁愿做一个小屁孩？
- Um, not exactly.
- 嗯，不完全是。
- Weenie Hut Jr.'s is
now hiring managers.
- 小威尼小屋 (Weenie Hut Jr.) 是
现在正在招聘经理。
Your responsibilities
will include...
你的责任
将包括...
- Whoa.
- 哇哦。
- Kicking back, relaxing,
and letting robots
- 踢回来，放松，
并让机器人
do all of the grunt work.
完成所有繁重的工作。
- Righteous.
- 正义。
[slurping]
[发出声音]
- Apply now
to Weenie Hut Jr.'s
- 立即申请
前往 Weenie Hut Jr. 的
and become a pivotal cog
in the corporate machine.
并成为关键齿轮
在公司机器上。
[static whirs]
- A manager?
[静电呼呼声]
- 经理？
That's for me!
那是给我的！
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
- Whoa!
- So long, Krusty Krab!
- 哇！
- 再见，蟹堡王！
- So long!
- 这么久！
- Where is that
blasted cashier?
-那是哪里
该死的收银员？
He's already an hour late.
他已经迟到一个小时了。
And who the heck
is this old lady?
到底是谁
这是老太太吗？
- I smell pickles.
- 我闻到了泡菜的味道。
- Mr. Krabs,
isn't Squidward looking
- 蟹老板先生，
看起来不像章鱼哥
better than ever these days?
这些天比以往任何时候都好？
- What?
That ain't Squidward.
- 什么？
那不是章鱼哥。
- Hmm?
It's not?
- 唔？
它不是？
Why is she wearing his hat?
她为什么戴着他的帽子？
Where is he?
Is he lost?
他在哪儿？
他迷路了吗？
Why is he so late?
Squidward!
他为什么这么晚？
章鱼哥！
[panicked panting]
[惊慌地喘气]
I'm coming to find you!
我来找你了！
[grunting]
Squidward!
[咕噜声]
章鱼哥！
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
- Uh-huh.
- 呃哈。
- Ah!
- 啊！
- Yeah, mm-hmm.
- 是的，嗯嗯。
- Squidward!
- 章鱼哥！
Oh, I'm so glad I found you!
哦，我很高兴找到你！
Now, let's get you back
to the Krusty Krab.
现在，让我们带你回来
到蟹堡王。
- Oh, I don't think so.
- 哦，我不这么认为。
I'm not going back
to the Krusty Krab ever.
我不会回去
永远的蟹堡王。
[grunts]
Because now I am a pivotal cog
[咕哝]
因为现在我是一个关键的齿轮
in the corporate machine.
在公司机器上。
- Oh, no!
That sounds horrible.
- 哦，不！
听起来很可怕。
- Oh, no. It sounds like
I'm the manager here.
- 哦，不。听起来像
我是这里的经理。
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
- Which also means I decide
- 这也意味着我决定
who stays and who goes.
谁留下，谁走。
Oh, Weenie Bots.
哦，维尼机器人。
Kick out this riffraff.
把这个痞子赶出去。
Both:
As you command, Weenie.
两者：
遵照你的命令，维尼。
- [whimpering]
- [呜咽]
Whoa!
哇！
- Attention, Weenie Bots.
- 注意，Weenie 机器人。
As your new manager,
作为你的新经理，
I'll be making
a few changes around here.
我会做
这里有一些变化。
- Uh-oh.
- 呃哦。
- All music in the jukebox
will now be...
- 自动点唱机中的所有音乐
现在将是...
smooth jazz.
流畅的爵士乐。
All Weenie-themed art
所有以威尼为主题的艺术作品
will now be fine art.
现在将成为美术。
And, lastly,
under no circumstances
最后，
在任何情况下
is anyone allowed
to interrupt my manager time.
任何人都可以
打扰我的经理时间。
[door slams]
[关门声]
[sighs contentedly]
Being a manager is hard work.
[满足地叹气]
成为一名经理是一项艰苦的工作。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Boss Weenie, you must
take out the trash.
- 维尼老板，你必须
把垃圾拿出来。
- Why can't you do it?
- 为什么你做不到？
- My extension cord
won't reach.
- 我的延长线
达不到。
- [grunts] Still better...
- [咕哝]还是更好...
[grunts]
Than the Krusty...
[咕哝]
比库斯蒂...
[grunts]
Krab.
[咕哝]
蟹。
[sighs]
[叹气]
[garage door slams]
[车库门关上]
[shattering]
[破碎]
[shouting, grunts]
[喊叫，咕哝]
Hey!
Open that door!
嘿！
打开那扇门！
[bots laughing]
[机器人大笑]
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
both: Hooray.
Celebration.
两人：万岁。
庆典。
Celebration.
Glug, glug, glug.
咕噜，咕噜，咕噜。
- Huh?
- 啊？
[growling]
[咆哮]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Aah!
啊啊！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- Oh, good.
You are back.
- 哦，很好。
你回来了。
- Weenie.
- 维尼。
- [growling]
- [咆哮]
[exclaims]
[惊呼]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
All right, Squidward.
好吧，章鱼哥。
It's time for a little
managerial work.
是时候稍微
管理工作。
"How to Repair Unruly Robots."
“如何修理不守规矩的机器人。”
Hmm.
唔。
[tools clattering]
[工具碰撞声]
[bell dings]
[铃声]
[sighs]
That ought to do the trick.
[叹气]
这应该能解决问题。
Weenie Bots, bring me a weenie.
威尼机器人，给我来一个威尼。
both:
Yes, Mr. Manager.
两者：
是的，经理先生。
[machinery whirring]
[机器的呼呼声]
[sizzling]
[嘶嘶声]
- [chomping]
Oh.
- [咀嚼]
哦。
I did it!
我做到了！
They're perfect employees now.
他们现在是完美的员工。
Weenie Bots, run the store.
Weenie Bots，经营商店。
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
I'm having manager time.
我有经理时间。
both:
Yes, Mr. Manager.
两者：
是的，经理先生。
[customers clamoring]
[顾客叫嚷]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
[bell dings]
[铃声]
- Ooh!
- 哦！
- [playing clarinet off-key]
- [单簧管走调]
[bell dings]
- [munching]
[铃声]
- [咀嚼]
[cash register bell dings,
slurping]
[收银机铃响，
吸食]
[cash register bell dings]
[收银铃声响起]
[crowd sighing contentedly]
[众人满足地叹息]
♪ ♪
[music box lullaby playing]
[音乐盒摇篮曲演奏]
- [screams]
- Mr. Manager.
- [尖叫]
- 经理先生。
- Can't you see
I'm trying to sleep?
- 你看不到吗
我想睡觉？
I mean manage.
我的意思是管理。
- The president
- 总统
of the Weenie Hut Corporation
is arriving.
威尼小屋公司
即将抵达。
- [panicked yelping]
Why didn't you say so?
- [惊慌地尖叫]
你为什么不这么说？
[panting, grunting]
[气喘吁吁，咕哝]
Oh.
哦。
[regal music]
[富丽堂皇的音乐]
♪ ♪
What a weenie.
真是个小家伙。
- Weenie J. Weiner.
- 维尼·J·维纳。
The J stands for Junior.
J 代表少年。
You must be
Squidward Q. Tentacles.
你一定是
章鱼哥 Q. 触手。
- The Q stands for Quincy.
- Q 代表昆西。
To what do I owe this honor?
我凭什么获得这份荣誉？
- Your success has been all
the buzz down at headquarters.
- 你的成功就是一切
总部的喧闹声减弱了。
- Oh!
- 哦！
- So I came straightaway
to offer you
- 所以我马上就来了
为您提供
the big promotion.
大促销。
- Finally, someone
recognizes my worth.
- 终于有人了
认可我的价值。
[camera shutter clicks]
Oh.
[相机快门声]
哦。
- But, first,
you'll need to take
- 但是，首先，
你需要采取
our upper-management course.
我们的高层管理课程。
Please, step
into my weeniecopter.
请迈步
进入我的小直升机。
♪ ♪
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- Welcome
to Weenie Hut Senior's!
- 欢迎
到 Weenie Hut Senior's！
- Oh, wow.
- 哦，哇。
both:
Congratulations, Weenie.
两者：
恭喜你，维尼。
- Congratulations, Weenie.
- 恭喜你，维尼。
- There sure are a lot
of robots working here.
- 肯定有很多
在这里工作的机器人。
- Yes, robots
are so much more efficient
- 是的，机器人
效率更高
and sanitary.
和卫生。
- Welcome, Weenie.
- 欢迎，维尼。
- Please, have a seat.
- 请坐。
Now lie back
and think of weenies.
现在躺下
并想到小家伙。
- What exactly
is this management course?
- 到底是什么
这是管理课程吗？
- Well, you see, Squidward,
we are going to turn you
- 嗯，你看，章鱼哥，
我们将把你转向
into the most efficient manager
you can be...
成为最有效率的管理者
你可以...
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
- By turning you into a...
[machinery whirring]
- 通过把你变成...
[机器的呼呼声]
Robot.
机器人。
- Oh, a robot,
well, that sounds just--
- 哦，一个机器人，
嗯，听起来只是——
[screams]
[尖叫声]
Help me!
帮我！
- Oh, we are helping you,
Squidward.
- 哦，我们正在帮助你，
章鱼哥。
You will be...
[machinery whirring]
你将会...
[机器的呼呼声]
One of us.
我们中的一员。
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
- Typical.
- 典型的。
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- [cackling]
- [咯咯笑]
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
Oh!
哦！
- [cackling]
[cannon fires]
- [咯咯笑]
[大炮开火]
- Huh?
- 啊？
- Ahoy there, Squidward.
- 嘿，章鱼哥。
We're here to save you.
我们是来拯救你的。
- How did you even know
I was here?
- 你怎么知道的
我在这儿？
- [cackling]
- [咯咯笑]
- I knew you were in danger.
- 我知道你有危险。
My squiddy sense was tingling.
我的鱿鱼感感到刺痛。
- I don't want to know
what that means.
- 我不想知道
这意味着什么。
Just get me out of here!
带我离开这里！
- All right, SpongeBob,
load her up.
- 好吧，海绵宝宝，
加载她。
- She's ready!
- 她准备好了！
[grunts] Watch your head.
[咕噜声]小心你的头。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- Whoo-hoo!
- 呼呼！
Pinchy, pinchy.
捏捏，捏捏。
- [cackling]
Huh?
- [咯咯笑]
啊？
- Cutie, cutie, cutie, cutie.
- 小可爱，小可爱，小可爱，小可爱。
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
- That brat's gonna burst!
- 这小子要爆炸了！
- [screaming]
[alarm blaring]
- [尖叫]
[警报声]
- Yummy weenie.
- 美味的维尼。
- Ow.
- [exclaims]
- 噢。
- [惊呼]
- Looks like we got here
just in time.
- 看来我们到了这里
正好。
Good to see ya, pal.
- Oof!
很高兴见到你，朋友。
- 噢！
[machinery whirring]
[机器的呼呼声]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- Order up, Squidward!
[bell dinging]
- 下令吧，章鱼哥！
[铃声]
Gee, it sure is great
to have you back.
哎呀，这确实很棒
让你回来。
- Sigh.
Please unplug me.
- 叹息。
请拔掉我的插头。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
- "The belly of inspiration
lies in the midst of your gut."
——《灵感之腹》
就在你的肠道之中。”
[sighs]
[叹气]
Welp, I better return this
wonderful book to the library
好吧，我最好退回这个
去图书馆的好书
before it's due.
在到期之前。
Ah!
啊!
[groans]
[呻吟]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
SpongeBob, what did I tell you
about standing too close to me?
海绵宝宝，我告诉你什么了
是因为站得离我太近吗？
- Oh, you said...
- 哦，你说...
[imitating Squidward] If you
keep standing too close to me,
[模仿章鱼哥] 如果你
一直站得离我太近
I'm going to trip over you.
我会被你绊倒。
- I rest my case...
- 我休息一下...
and my face.
和我的脸。
- [normal voice]
Sorry, Squidward.
- [正常声音]
对不起，章鱼哥。
I just wanted to invite you
to go with me and Patrick.
我只是想邀请你
跟我和帕特里克一起去。
We have a really
fun day planned.
我们有一个真正
计划了有趣的一天。
Mm!
- Oh, shucks and golly gee.
毫米！
- 哦，天哪。
I really wish
I could come and have big fun
我真的希望
我可以来玩得很开心
with you and Patrick.
和你还有帕特里克。
Eeh!
呃！
- But?
- 但？
- But I have to return
my favorite book
- 但我必须回去
我最喜欢的书
of daily affirmations
to the library by noon,
每天的肯定
中午到图书馆，
or I'll have to pay a penalty.
否则我将不得不支付罚款。
- You mean this book?
[clears throat]
- 你是说这本书吗？
[清嗓子]
"In life, 'tis better to play
hide-and-seek with the trees
“生活中，最好是玩
和树捉迷藏
than checkers with the wind."
比随风跳棋。”
Hey, that's what
Patrick always says.
嘿，就是这样
帕特里克总是这样说。
- No, he doesn't.
- 不，他没有。
Get your own affirmations.
得到你自己的肯定。
[blimp humming overhead]
[飞艇在头顶嗡嗡作响]
- Hi, SpongeBob.
- 嗨，海绵宝宝。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Here we go!
开始了！
- Ha, 9:00 a.m.--
- 哈，上午 9:00--
plenty of time
before the deadline.
有足够的时间
在截止日期之前。
Yeah, you have to get up
pretty early in the morning.
是的，你必须起床
一大早。
And I did.
我做到了。
[mutters]
Ah, there it is--
[嘀咕]
啊，在那里——
book returns, top floor.
还书，顶楼。
[elevator bell dings]
[电梯铃声]
both: Hey, Squidward.
Going up?
两人：嘿，章鱼哥。
上去吗？
- Ah!
Uh, I'll take the next one.
- 啊！
呃，我去拿下一张。
[elevator bell dinging]
[电梯铃声响起]
[gasps]
[喘气]
[sighs contentedly]
[满足地叹气]
both: Squidward!
- Huh?
两人：章鱼哥！
- 啊？
both: Hold the door!
两人：把门扶住！
- Close the door.
Close the door. Close the door.
- 关门。
关门。关门。
[both panting,
elevator bell dinging]
[两人都气喘吁吁，
电梯铃声响起]
[both straining]
[双方都紧张]
- Thanks for holding
the door, Squidward.
- 谢谢你的坚持
门，章鱼哥。
- [grumbles]
- [抱怨]
I thought you yo-yos
had a big day of fun planned.
我还以为你哟哟
计划了美好的一天。
Why aren't you there?
你为什么不在？
- We are there, Squidward,
- 我们在那里，章鱼哥，
because today is...
因为今天是...
both:
Elevator Riding Day!
两者：
乘坐电梯日！
Wa-hoo!
哇呼！
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
I feel my anger.
我感到我的愤怒。
But I am calm
like a plate of linguine.
但我很平静
就像一盘扁面条。
Patrick, be a dear
帕特里克，做个亲爱的
and hit the top-floor button
for me, please.
然后点击顶楼按钮
为我，请。
- Top floor!
- 顶楼！
Going up--right after we
hit all these other floors.
上来——就在我们之后
到达所有其他楼层。
- [gasps] What are you doing?
- [喘气]你在做什么？
- Yeah, Patrick,
what are you doing?
- 是的，帕特里克，
你在做什么？
You missed one.
你错过了一个。
Boop.
Every floor counts!
噗。
每层楼都很重要！
Hey!
嘿！
- Top floor first.
Top floor first.
- 首先是顶层。
先顶楼。
[electricity crackling]
[电力噼啪声]
[elevator rumbling]
[电梯隆隆声]
Oh, no, we're trapped,
trapped like sardines!
哦，不，我们被困住了，
像沙丁鱼一样被困！
- Don't worry, Squidward.
- 别担心，章鱼哥。
This happens to us
all the time.
这发生在我们身上
一直。
- Yeah, last week we only had
to wait five hours.
- 是的，上周我们只
要等五个小时。
- "Five hours"?
- “五个小时”？
That's past
the book-return deadline!
那已经过去了
还书期限到了！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Like a plate of linguine.
[sighs contentedly]
就像一盘扁面条。
[满足地叹气]
Hey, why don't we just use
the emergency phone
嘿，我们为什么不直接使用
紧急电话
and call for help?
并寻求帮助？
- Well, if you want
to do it the easy way.
- 好吧，如果你愿意的话
以简单的方式做到这一点。
[line trilling]
- Hello?
[行颤音]
- 你好？
- Hello.
Oh, thank Neptune.
- 你好。
哦，谢谢海王星。
- Oh, thank Neptune.
- 哦，谢谢海王星。
- I didn't think
this phone would work.
- 我没想到
这个电话可以用。
- I didn't think
this phone would work.
- 我没想到
这个电话可以用。
- I'm trapped in an elevator.
- 我被困在电梯里了。
- Stop saying what I'm saying!
- 别再说我说的话了！
- Stop saying what I'm saying.
- 别再说我说的话了。
- I really am trapped
in an elevator.
- 我真的被困住了
在电梯里。
- I really am trapped
in an elevator.
- 我真的被困住了
在电梯里。
[both growling]
- Gosh!
[双方咆哮]
- 天哪！
Oh, you're no help at all.
哦，你根本帮不上忙。
- [rasping]
You're no help at all.
- [刺耳]
你根本没有帮助。
both:
Idiot!
两者：
白痴！
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
"Relaxation is the tippy toe
to tranquility."
“放松就是踮起脚尖
到宁静。”
[sighs]
[叹气]
- Now you relax.
- 现在你放松了。
Patrick can fix it.
帕特里克可以解决这个问题。
- Yeah, my dad
was an elevator surgeon
- 是的，我的爸爸
是一名电梯外科医生
for a whole day.
一整天。
- He was a what?
- 他是什么？
- Screwdriver.
- 螺丝刀。
Hmm.
唔。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
And now to connect
the right wires.
现在要连接
正确的电线。
[electricity fizzing]
[电嘶嘶声]
That's not it.
不是这个。
- Wait, Patrick, don't!
- 等等，帕特里克，别这样！
- [growls]
- [咆哮]
- Patrick.
- 帕特里克.
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- Enough!
Get me out of here!
- 足够的！
带我离开这里！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[shouts]
[喊叫]
Why won't these
stupid doors open?
为什么这些不会
愚蠢的门打开了？
[elevator bell dings]
[电梯铃声]
Huh?
啊？
- Squidward!
- 章鱼哥！
Grab my hand!
抓住我的手！
- Huh?
- 啊？
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[mellow music]
[柔和的音乐]
♪ ♪
- That was a close one,
huh, Squidward?
- 那是一场亲密的比赛，
哈，章鱼哥？
- What's that?
- 那是什么？
both:
A door.
两者：
一扇门。
[ethereal music]
[空灵的音乐]
- [straining]
Hurry!
- [紧张]
快点！
- Good luck, losers.
- 祝你好运，失败者。
- Thanks, Squidward.
- 谢谢，章鱼哥。
- Finally, that book
is getting returned on time.
- 最后，那本书
正在准时返回。
Thank Neptune!
感谢海王星！
both: Hey, Squidward.
- Huh?
两人：嘿，章鱼哥。
- 啊？
both:
You're back.
两者：
你回来了。
[suspenseful musical sting]
【悬疑的音乐刺痛】
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
both:
Now give us a boost.
两者：
现在给我们一个动力。
- "Serenity floats
on an ocean of cheese."
——“宁静漂浮
在奶酪的海洋上。”
[sighs contentedly]
[满足地叹气]
[stomach growling]
[肚子咕咕叫]
I'm starving.
我饿死了。
How long have we been stuck
in here?
我们被困了多久
在这里？
- Don't worry, Squidward.
- 别担心，章鱼哥。
While you were out,
I ordered a pizza.
当你外出时，
我点了一份披萨。
- Give me that, you pea brain.
- 给我这个，你这个豌豆脑子。
We can call for help.
我们可以打电话寻求帮助。
[cell phone beeping]
[手机提示音]
Of course.
当然。
[elevator bell dings]
- Pizza delivery.
[电梯铃声]
- 披萨外送。
- Thanks.
- 谢谢。
- We're saved!
- 我们得救了！
[alarm ringing]
Patrick!
[警报响起]
帕特里克！
[straining]
[紧张]
- All right!
Let's eat!
- 好的！
我们吃饭吧！
- Eat what?
- 吃什么？
[stomach growling]
[肚子咕咕叫]
- Now I'm starving, and my book
is going to be late.
- 现在我快饿死了，我的书
就要迟到了。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
"Only when all is lost can
you see inside your nostrils
“只有当一切都失去的时候
你看到你鼻孔里面
and find yourself."
并找到你自己。”
[sighs contentedly]
[满足地叹气]
[both inhaling,
exhaling deeply]
[同时吸气，
深深地呼气]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Oh, ah.
哦，啊。
[gasps, laughs]
[喘气，大笑]
I'm free!
我自由了！
After 22 years,
22年后，
I finally got
out of that cursed elevator.
我终于得到了
从那个该死的电梯里出来。
[laughing]
[笑]
W-what?
Huh?
什、什么？
啊？
[elevator bell dings]
Another elevator?
[电梯铃声]
另一部电梯？
[elevator bell dings]
[screams]
[电梯铃声]
[尖叫声]
- Greetings, stranger.
- 你好，陌生人。
Welcome to our island
of tranquility.
欢迎来到我们的岛屿
的宁静。
both: Going up.
[gong sounding]
两人：上升。
[锣声响起]
- This is a lot nicer
than my old elevator.
- 这好多了
比我的旧电梯。
Mind if I stay here a while?
介意我在这里待一会儿吗？
- You'll have to ask the king.
- 你得去问国王。
both: Going up.
[gong sounding]
两人：上升。
[锣声响起]
- The king?
- Did someone say my name?
- 国王？
- 有人说了我的名字吗？
- Oh, wise King Squidward.
- 哦，聪明的章鱼哥国王。
This weary traveler
wishes to stay with us.
这位疲惫的旅人
希望和我们在一起。
- Please, King,
can we keep him?
- 国王，请您
我们可以留住他吗？
- Hmm.
Let me consult the book.
- 唔。
让我查阅一下书吧。
[bell dings, ethereal singing]
[钟声叮叮，歌声空灵]
both: The book.
The book.
两者：书。
这本书。
- "A friend in need is
a servant guaranteed."
- “有需要的朋友是
保证有仆人。”
[bell dings]
[铃声]
The book says yes!
书上说是的！
both: Going up!
[gong sounding]
两人：上升！
[锣声响起]
- Of course you can stay
with us, my child.
- 当然你可以留下来
和我们在一起，我的孩子。
We'll teach you
the ways of the book.
我们会教你
书中的方法。
And you'll get to spend
every day
你会花
每天
worshipping me.
崇拜我。
[eerie music]
[诡异的音乐]
both:
You'll be just like us.
两者：
你会和我们一样。
- Oh, gee.
- 哦，天哪。
Oh, hey, is that the doorbell?
哦，嘿，那是门铃吗？
I-I think I left the oven on.
我-我想我没关烤箱。
[laughs]
Whoo!
[笑]
呼！
[screams]
[thud]
[尖叫声]
[砰]
- Listen, my people,
- 听着，我的人民，
the book says it's time
for me to relax.
书上说是时候了
让我放松。
[knocking]
Huh?
[敲门声]
啊？
- Hello?
Are you all right in there?
- 你好？
你在里面还好吗？
- Yes, yes, I'm all right!
Get me out!
- 是的，是的，我没事！
放我出去！
Oh, thank you.
哦，谢谢。
Thank you for rescuing me
from these stupid--
谢谢你救了我
来自这些愚蠢的人——
- Are you Squidward Tentacles?
- Yes.
- 你是章鱼哥触手吗？
- 是的。
- We've been looking for you.
- 我们一直在找你。
We're the library police.
我们是图书馆警察。
You have a withdrawn book
that is now 30 seconds overdue.
您有一本已撤回的书
现在已逾期 30 秒。
And you'll have to pay
the penalty.
你必须付出代价
处罚。
- What do I owe you--
like, a nickel?
- 我欠你什么--
比如，五分钱？
[laughs]
- You're going to library jail.
[笑]
- 你要去图书馆监狱。
- [sighs contentedly]
Library jail--
- [满足地叹气]
图书馆监狱——
how relaxing.
多么放松啊。
"I appreciate myself
by taking time to recharge
“我很欣赏自己
花时间充电
"with my best friend--
“和我最好的朋友——
me."
我。”
[sighs contentedly]
[满足地叹气]
[elevator whirring, bell dings]
[电梯呼呼、铃声叮叮]
both: Oh, wise king,
we missed you so.
两人：噢，明智的国王，
我们非常想念你。
- Why, Neptune?
- 为什么，海王星？
Why?
为什么？
- We had overdue books, too.
- 我们也有过期的书。
both: Going up.
[gong sounding]
两人：上升。
[锣声响起]
- [grunting]
Going up!
- [咕哝]
上升！